A Team Nanban (594mgnav) Release
Per the Special Anti-Terrorism Measures Act,
（オペレーター）
対テロ特別措置法に基づき―
we now place all terminals in the designated area
under Public Security's electronic control.
指定区域の全端末を
電子的制圧下に置きます
"Give back our water!"
（アナウンサー）
ハリマダラ重工業に対する
サイバーテロにより 内務省は…
Anticipating that cyberterrorism against
Harimadara Heavy Industries will lead
- to a shutdown of operations, Home Affairs has...
- HQ to Squad 357.
（男性）本庁より357機動隊
Transfer command to Section 9.
現場指揮を公安９課へ委譲せよ
これは最優先事項である
This is Priority One.
（デモ参加者たち）
人殺し！ 人殺し！
Murderers!
Murderers!!
水を返せ！
Give back our water!
（アナウンサー）
抗議行動が激しさを増す中―
- Give back our water!! - Despite increasingly
fierce protests, a contract has just been signed
クザン共和国の
国営水企業と―
- Despite increasingly fierce protests,
a contract has just been signed
between a Kuzan water company
and the Japanese giant Harimadara.
我が国 大手の
ハリマダラ社の間で―
契約が締結されました
"Give water to the war orphans!!"
"Give water to the war orphans!"
（素子(もとこ)）始まるわ
It's starting.
（オペレーター１）
範囲修正後の全回線クリア
All channels within the revised limits are clear.
（オペレーター２）
内務省 国交省管轄ライン掌握
All Home Affairs
and MLIT lines now under our control.
（オペレーター３）
ドミネーション･レディ
Ready for domination.
（荒巻(あらまき)）制圧開始
Begin.
（オペレーター１）ビルおよび
周辺道路のライフライン―
All lifelines, surveillance, etc.
for the building and roads now dominated.
監視装置 電子系等
全てドミネート
（オペレーター２）
地域内の4,022人の電脳―
Profiling cyberbrains and terminals of
4,022 people in the area.
および 端末をプロファイル
要追跡項目 1,102件
1,102 require follow-up.
Aramaki! I'm not giving you my crime scene!
（８課課員）荒巻
貴様に現場を譲る気はない！
（６課課員）こちら ６課
This is Section 6.
Who said you could infiltrate our comm lines?!
我々の回線に侵入するとは
どういうことだ！
（荒巻）必要なのは
被害を未然に防ぐことで―
We need to prevent casualties,
not play departmental musical chairs!
現場の椅子取りゲームではない！
襲撃手段すら
掌握できなかった責任は誰が取る！
Or will you take the fall when we can't
even pin down their means of attack?!
Chief Aramaki, explain yourself.
（北原(きたはら)）荒巻部長 説明を
北原副大臣殿
Vice-Minister Kitahara.
例の契約祝賀会に ご列席中と
聞きましたが？
I thought you were attending the celebratory banquet?
あなたの警告どおりになったと？
What you warned me of is happening, then?
３時間前 カルディス人グループが
行動を始めたと―
We got an anonymous tip that
a Qhardi group mobilized three hours ago.
匿名の通報がありました
Anonymous?
匿名？ 信頼できるのですか？
Can you trust it?
（荒巻）はい
Yes. The Yotsubashi Building area is
definitely the target.
四(よつ)つ橋(ばし)ビル周辺が
攻撃目標であることは―
間違いありません
（バトー）
サル部長 張り切ってやがる
The old ape's sure fired up,
considering we're flying blind here.
情報負けした事件だってのによ
Batou, this is the outfit
we've been after ever since
（素子）ハリマダラ重工業への
電脳汚染から４か月―
the cyber-contamination at Harimadara
four months ago.
私たちが追ってきた獲物よ バトー
"We"? You mean you.
私たち？ お前がだろ
（トグサ）
これ 少佐が作ったんですか？
Did you make this, Major?
オモチャじゃねえぞ 新入り
It ain't a toy, rookie.
（素子）軍用の疑似体験通信よ
枝がつく可能性はゼロに近いわ
It's a military-grade virtual comm link.
It's almost impossible for hackers to listen in.
（イシカワ）９課がドミネを強行
じき 号令だ
Section 9 forced the domination through.
We'll have orders soon.
（素子）実行犯を１人さらえ
Nab one of the terrorists.
I want bait to draw out our prey.
私たちの獲物を釣る餌が欲しい
（トグサ）例の
超ウィザード級ハッカー ―
Is it that super-wizard-class hacker,
Fire-Starter?
ファイア･スターターですか？
Isn't that just what you want?
（バトー）
お前の願望じゃねえのか？
本当に黒幕がいるのかも
分からねえってのに
We don't even know if there's really
someone pulling the strings.
（素子）私の願いは
正式な特殊部隊の設立よ
What I want is to formally establish
my spec ops team.
正体不明の敵が怖いなら
外れなさい
If you're scared of unknown enemies, drop out.
Piss off.
（バトー）ふざけんな
"Corporate Killers"
（トグサ）
電脳会議中に運転か… 事故るぞ
（バトー）
そんなド素人は てめえだけだ
Our status as an independent
offensive unit is riding on this.
我々が独立攻性でいられる瀬戸際だ
Public Security handles the incident,
and we handle what caused it.
公安が事件を 我々が核心をつかむ
行け
Go.
（オペレーター）
敵のゴーサインを傍受
The enemy just gave the go-ahead.
確保だ！
Capture them!
You deserve this...
Greedy rich-country bastards!
（実行犯１）
報いだ… 大国の強欲者ども！
（実行犯２）ああ…
（サイード）本日―
Today, we've followed the principle
of free trade
自由貿易の理念にのっとり―
to maintain fair prices that will spur
postwar economic recovery.
戦後復興を促す適正価格を
維持できました
（実行犯３）うっ… ぐ…
（ボーマ）
武器はこれだけ… おかしいぜ
This was his only weapon.
Something's fishy.
The riot squad opened fire?!
機動隊員の一斉射撃だと！
The west team's slaughtering protesters.
（バトー）
西側部隊がデモ隊を虐殺中だ
Some are even shooting other cops!
仲間を撃ってるのもいるぞ
（イシカワ）
前代未聞の同時ゴーストハックだ
It's the biggest simultaneous Ghost Hack ever.
信じられんが
そう考えるしかない
It's crazy, but it's the only explanation.
100名を同時に操る技術は
存在しない
There's no tech that'd control
100 people at once.
（バトー）実行犯まで皆殺しだ
The perps on my watch are all dead, too.
攻撃の根拠が何か
機動隊の回線を調べろ
Check the riot squad's lines
and find out what caused the attack.
（イシカワ）
スターターらしきログがあるが…
There's a log that might be Starter's, but...
では ハックではない
ウイルスだ
Then this isn't hacking.
It's a virus.
（イシカワ）
だが シーケンスに何も出ねえ
I don't see one in the sequence.
自己消滅する
スタックスネット型だ
It's a self-destructing Stuxnet-type.
集団を操るための
パッケージ化された行動を―
Someone must be sending packaged
actions meant to control groups.
送っているやつがいるはず
お前か…
You,eh?
（サイード）復興と独立を求め
私は悪魔の取引をした
I made a deal with the devil
for the sake of rebuilding and independence!
あなた方の望むとおりに
Just like you wanted!
その結果
銃による虐殺のあとで―
And it invited a second slaughter
by water and e-money
水と電脳マネーによる
２度目の虐殺を招いたのだ
to follow the first slaughter with guns!
- You said cyberbrain tech and the prosthetics industry
- I want a media blackout now.
マスコミの情報遮断を
最優先事項よ！
- Would build us a future,
- This is Priority One!
（サイード）我がカルディスタンに
もたらしたものは―
But hope wasn't
what they brought to Qhardistan!
希望などではなかった
民の誇りを吸い上げる
裏切りの根が―
They merely sowed the seeds of betrayal
深く張り巡らされただけだった！
that would grow to bleed away my people's pride!
Have a taste of what that felt like!
Then you'll have no choice
but to grant me asylum!
（サイード）その上で
私の亡命を受け入れざるをえない
この国は
平和主義の文明国なのだから！
Because this is a civilized, pacifist nation!
Oh, is it?
（素子）あら そう？
（ホヅミ）うっ… 光学迷彩！
Optical camouflage!
（エマ）ファイア･スターターは
止められない
You can't stop Fire-Starter.
私に枝をつけた！？
Someone hacked my line?!
（女性）ああっ…
（トグサ）少佐！？
Major?!
Saito!
（バトー）サイトー！
Shit.
くそっ…
Hello!
（ロジコマ）ハロー！
Give me a weapon!
（素子）武器を出せ
（ロジコマ）はーい
Okay!
Major, I'll be right there!
（バトー）
少佐 今 行くからな
Don't be stupid.
Go after the one who hacked me!
（素子）寝ぼけるな
私に枝をつけたやつを追え
On your knees!
（バトー）ひざまずけ！
I'll shoot you dead if you resist.
抵抗すると撃ち殺すぞ！
ふんっ！
（トグサ）
ぐっ う… いきなりかよ！
That was outta nowhere!
This was your job, moron!
（バトー）
バカ！ お前が運ぶ役だろ！
Sorry! That was an accident.
（ロジコマ）すみません
落としちゃいました
Equip some handrails!
（素子）手すりくらい装備しろ
Do it, Saito.
（素子）やれ サイトー
（サイトー）
逃がしました すみません
I let him get away, sorry!
"Section 9 Office"
（荒巻）バカ者が！
ようやく仕事を引き受けたと
思ったら―
You finally take the job,
and then you execute someone on the national Net?
全国ネットで公開処刑か！
私が？ 証拠は ないはずよ
Who, me? You have no proof.
Are you claiming you had no choice?
（荒巻）他に手段がなかったと？
超ウィザード級ハッカーにして
エース･ユニット
You're a super-wizard-class hacker
in an ace unit.
Was the Army overestimating you
when it rated you five stars?
軍が お前につけた５つ星評価は
買いかぶりか？
（素子）ウイルスと
あの全身義体の少女は？
Tell me about the virus and that heavy cyborg girl.
（荒巻）電脳ウイルスは検出されず
No cyber-virus was detected.
The girl's name is Emma Tsuda.
少女の名はツダ･エマ
ゲームアプリメーカーとして
ネットでは知られた存在だそうだ
Apparently she's famous on the Net
as a game app maker.
（素子）
逮捕から９時間たって それ？
Nine hours after her arrest,
that's all you've got?
元陸軍情報部
特Ａ監察官の荒巻部長ときたら―
I guess a former Special A Rank inspector
for the Army like you
gets to have lots of talented subordinates.
さぞ いい部下を
たくさん持ってるのね
（荒巻）
実行犯数名を生かして捕らえた
My people's dedicated effort got
multiple perps captured alive.
人員の献身的な働きのおかげだ
（素子）偉いわ
Wow, great work arresting
some mindless packaged drones.
パッケージ化された人形ばかり
逮捕して
（バトー）ハァ…
特務権限さえあれば 防げたわ
We could've stopped it
if we'd had special authority.
ならば 愚連隊を気取らず
うちの所属になれ
Then stop playing gangsters and join Section 9.
内務省直下でないかぎり―
Unless you work directly for Home Affairs,
you do get official oversight
and you don't get secrecy.
監察部のチャンネルがついて
機密性が失われる
Can you guarantee I'd be able to stay myself?
（素子）
私が私でいられる保障は？
Cutting-edge equipment can protect
cyberbrains and prosthetic bodies.
（荒巻）電脳や義体も
最新の装備で守られる
And my Ghost? My beliefs?
私のゴーストや信念は？
（荒巻）
実力次第だ 予算も考慮する
Depends on how skilled you are.
I'll even consider a budget.
Create an international counterterrorist agency for us
国際的対テロ機関の創設
レンジャー大隊と同額予算
with the same budget as the Rangers.
（バトー）あっ 俺
ちょっと 飯 食ってくるわ
I'm gonna go eat.
（ホヅミ）久しぶりだな 荒巻
Aramaki, it's been a while.
Colonel Hozumi.
What brings Army intelligence here?
（荒巻）ホヅミ大佐
陸軍情報部が何の用だ？
I'll take the girl now.
（ホヅミ）娘を渡してもらおう
説明は？
Care to explain?
They're from a squad I trust.
彼女らは わしが信頼する部隊だ
Ex-major Motoko Kusanagi, of the 501.
（ホヅミ）草薙(くさなぎ)素子三佐
元501機関所属
Hated your master so much
you became a stray, eh?
飼い主を嫌って
野良犬になったか
Your intel's dated.
They recreated my rank.
情報古いわ 今は少佐よ
The cyber-virus used is crucial for us to investigate.
現場で使用された
電脳ウイルスは―
我々の要追跡対象だ
Explain why it's crucial, please.
どう重要なのか説明してくれ
（ホヅミ）洗脳 ゴースト侵入
疑似記憶の形成の―
It's a triple package of brainwashing,
Ghost infiltration, and false memory creation.
トリプルパッケージだ
疑似記憶？
False memory? Last I checked,
the government doesn't admit that's possible,
多数の被害報告がありながら
政府は可能性を認めていないはずだ
despite all the reports.
Virus units entered this country via a certain broker.
（ホヅミ）
あるブローカーを通して―
ウイルス･ユニットが
国内に持ち込まれた
Trust me: You won't even manage to indict that girl.
いいか 貴様では あの娘を
起訴にすら持ち込めんぞ
Unfortunately, she's been transferred to Unit 501.
（荒巻）残念だが
娘は501機関に移された
（ホヅミ）いつ？
When?
協同打診に わしが合意した時点で
The moment I agreed to their request for cooperation.
I've never thought you were clever, but this?
（ホヅミ）昔から
利口ではないと思っていたが―
You'll regret any foolish stubbornness.
くだらん意地を張ると後悔するぞ
Terror by false memories...
疑似記憶を用いたテロか…
ついに
お前の主張どおりになったな 少佐
Your claims are finally proven, Major.
So is the existence of a virus
that enables Ghost-hacking.
ゴーストハックを可能にする
ウイルスの実在もね
仕事だ 娘を501機関へ護送しろ
Here's your next job: Escort the girl to Unit 501.
何？ 本当に打診があったの？
What? There was really a request?
（荒巻）
国防大臣のサイン付きでな
Signed by the Defense Minister.
Now give me one of your men in exchange.
代わりに１人 わしにつけろ
Did your scary ex-colleague make you want a guard?
（素子）元同僚に脅されて
護衛が欲しい？
I want information sharing.
Go renew old workplace friendships.
（荒巻）情報の共有だ
古巣で旧交を温めろ
Can I ask one thing?
（素子）１つ聞いていい？
（荒巻）何だ？
What is it?
Assuming I did shoot her...
（素子）
私が あの女を撃ったとして―
...why didn't you use my Ghost
infiltration key to stop me?
なぜ 私のゴースト侵入キーを
使って止めなかったの？
I can't answer hypothetical questions.
仮の話では答えられんな
I see.
（素子）そう
This is Dr. Zhinzhee Bekka Arr Thied,
the one the Major killed.
（イシカワ）少佐が射殺した
ジンジ･ベッカ･アル･サイード博士
カルディス人だが
クザン王立大学を主席で卒業
She's Qhardi, but she graduated
from Kuzan Royal University as Valedictorian.
A big player in Kuzan water importation
since the provisional government days.
同国の水輸入の立役者で
暫定政権時代から活躍してた
（バトー）
…が てめえの民族が―
But she supported terrorism when she realized
the world would forsake her people, eh?
世界から見捨てられたのを悟って
テロに荷担か
She's smart and she's got motive,
but she's not a hacker.
（素子）動機はあるし優秀だが
ハッカーではない
Someone else packaged this.
こいつをパッケージ化した
人物がいる
What about the girl we captured?
（トグサ）
現場で押さえた あの少女は？
（イシカワ）名はツダ･エマ
Her name's Emma Tsuda.
A 17-year-old war orphan.
戦災孤児の17歳
She makes hit cyberbrain games,
which she copyrights under the name "Tin Man".
電脳ネット･ゲームの
ヒットメーカーで―
ソフトの権利名義は“ティンマン”
ティンマン… ブリキのきこり？
"Tin Man"... As in The Wizard of Oz?
何だ そりゃ？
What's that?
- In spite of everything, I still believe
- Supposing she's a teenage super-hacker, how does she fit in?
（イシカワ）この娘が10代の
スーパーハッカーだとして―
事件のどこに当てはまる？
- that people are really good at heart
- Don't tell me she's the one you're after?
まさか こいつが
少佐の追ってた相手か？
- I wish to go on living even after my death.
- I'll know when I dive into her Ghost.
彼女のゴーストに
ダイブすれば分かる
Ishikawa, stay on the virus and the girl.
Saito, you go to Section 9.
イシカワはウイルスと娘
サイトーは９課へ
Paz and Borma, you release the bait.
パズとボーマは餌を放て
Batou, Togusa, and I will escort the girl.
バトーとトグサと私で
娘の護送だ
第２ラウンド始めるぞ
We're starting the second round.
Suggestion for you,
Miss "Hothead Who Charges In Blind".
情報負けしたまま前進する
イノシシねえちゃんに提案だ
いっそ 俺が隊長になって―
How about I become team leader
and lead us in a sensible retreat?
合理的撤退を指揮するってのは
どうだ？
Brave thing to say in my cyberbrain space.
（素子）
私の電脳空間で いい度胸だ
Step outside and let's fight!
（バトー）てめえ… 表出ろ！
Whoa, knock it off, you guys!
（トグサ）おい ちょっと
やめろよ ２人とも！
He's finally on the move.
（パズ）やっと動きやがった
退屈で死にそうだったぜ
（エンジンの音）
Thought I'd die of boredom!
It might be cool if we could ride in you.
お前 乗れたら面白いかもな
（ロジコマ１）
少佐が 人員運搬用シャフトを
整備課に申請中です
The Major requested a personnel transport shaft
from the Maintenance Department!
Will we pilot you from inside?
（バトー）中に入って操縦すんの
Isn't that our mobile arsenal?
Where would the weapons go?
（トグサ）走る武器庫だろ？
荷物はどうすんだ
We can just resupply each other.
If we armed this guy, he could be our backup.
（バトー）
隊員同士で補給すりゃいい
こいつ自身を武装させりゃ
バックアップになる
（トグサ）バックアップね…
Backup,eh?
なんで旧式のロジスティクスなんか
使ってんだ？
Why are we using an outdated Logistics model?
（バトー）少佐が望んだ予算を
サルが確保できず 代わりの備品さ
Ape-Face couldn't get the budget the Major wanted,
so he gave us these bots.
ニューロチップ型ＡＩは
ウイルスやハッキングに強いしな
Neurochip-type Als are hard to hack or infect, anyway.
それ廃棄寸前ってことか？
So basically, it was us or the junkyard?
What? Not good enough
for the ex-cop still wearing a necktie?
いまだに ネクタイ締めてる
元特捜刑事さんにゃ―
お気に召さねえか？
“品性は自分への信頼だ”って
死んだおやじが言ってたっけ
My late father said looking classy
shows faith in yourself.
あんた見てると分かるよ
元レンジャー
Watching you, ex-Ranger,
I see what he meant.
Bold words, kid.
言うねえ 若造が
Mr. Batou suggested modifying us
so people could ride us!
（ロジコマ２）バトー隊員から―
“私たちに乗れるようにしては”と
提案されました
I think it's a really great idea!
What do you think, Major?
とっても すてきだと思います
少佐は いかがお考えですか？
くだらない話をするな
Don't talk nonsense. I hate machines
who pretend to have personalities.
人格があるふりをする機械は
嫌いなの
（ロジコマ２）しゅ～ん…
（エレベーターの到着音）
（素子）来たぞ
She's here.
（素子）私に枝をつけて
わざと捕まったか？
Did you hack my line to
deliberately get yourself caught?
What is "Fire-Starter"?
Is it really the name of a hacker?
ファイア･スターターとは何だ？
本当にハッカーの名か？
Intelligence wants you.
Military courts don't do plea bargains, you know.
情報部が お前を欲しがっている
軍事法廷に司法取引はないぞ
（エマ）潮の香りがする
I smell seawater.
We aren't even allowed near the sea.
私たちは勝手に
海に近づくこともできない
Programmers are like weapons:
We're forbidden by law from moving freely.
プログラマーは武器と一緒で―
法律で自由な移動を
禁止されてるから
（素子）やはり 組織のハッカーか
So you are the group's hacker.
What are you after?
目的は何だ？
Long ago, glassblowers had no freedom,
because glasswork funded the state.
（エマ）昔のガラス職人は
自由がなかった
ガラスは政府の資金源だったから
ガラス職人が他の国に行くときは
両目を潰された
If they left the country,
they were blinded first.
亡命？ それで虐殺騒ぎを？
You're a refugee?
That's why you started a massacre?
（エマ）
電脳は人を幸せにすると思う？
Do you think cyberbrains make people happy?
あなたの記憶は確か？
Are your memories trustworthy?
Or were they planted by someone?
それとも 誰かに
植え付けられたもの？
マイクロマシン･ベースの
電脳化が実現したとき―
When micromachine-based cyberization came to pass,
experts worldwide warned us:
世界中の専門家が警告したわ
偽りの記憶が
犯罪に使われるって
"False memories will be used to commit crimes".
どの組織も
その技術を欲しがってる
Every organization wants that technology.
My technology.
私の技術を
You mean you successfully made
memory-manipulation tech?
記憶操作の技術を
確立したってのか？
Your memories might even be...
あなたの記憶も もしかして…
I'm diving right here, right now!
（素子）今 ここで
こいつのゴーストに潜る
Saw that coming.
…だと思ったぜ
We don't know what this virus is.
What if you're infected?
ウイルスの正体も不明なんだぞ
感染したらどうする？
（素子）
こいつの電脳ごと吹き飛ばすわ
I'll blow it away, and her cyberbrain with it.
A hacker who commits mass murder
just to escape deserves assassination.
逃亡目的の虐殺をやらかす
ハッカーなんて―
暗殺対象にしかならないでしょ
ダイブ中にかよ？
お前の電子戦術って 変態的だな
During your dive?!
Your cyber warfare style is twisted.
I prefer the term "super-wizard-class".
（素子）超ウィザード級と
言ってちょうだい
"Wizard"... Magician.
Magician who can't go home...
ウィザード… 魔法使い
帰れない魔法使い
I'm diving straight in through her line.
（素子）
ライン越えして 一気に潜るわ
Uh-huh, ignore protocol.
（バトー）マニュアル無視ね
Hey, something's weird.
おい 変だぞ…
You're being hacked!
They're doing it through her cyberbrain!
お前がハックされてる！
経路は そいつの電脳だ！
（バトー）どうなってる！？
ただのバックファイアじゃねえぞ
What's going on?
This isn't just backfire!
Emma... Danger... Emma...
（男性の声）
エマ 危ない エマ
You...
貴様…
少佐！
Major!
I'm sorry, Emma... I'm sorry.
（男性）
ごめんなさい エマ… ごめんなさい
It's okay. I wanted this.
（エマ）
いいの 私が望んだことだから
Don't cry, Brinda.
泣かないで ブリンダ
ゴーストが… ２つある？
There are two Ghosts in there?
（雨形(あまがた)）９課の介入は聞いている
I heard about Section 9's meddling.
You couldn't have shot her
before she started blabbing about asylum?
（雨形）亡命を口走る前に
撃てなかったのかね
That shooting is currently under investigation,
Deputy Director Amagata.
（荒巻）射殺犯は現在捜査中です
雨形審議官
あなたが審議に参加する
次世代主力兵器検討委員会…
I can imagine the profound effects
this incident will have
今回の事件の余波は
計りしれないものとお察しします
on the Next-Generation Weapons
Review Committee you serve on.
（雨形）歳末の
インダストリー･フェアも中止
The year-end industry fair has been cancelled.
And thanks to pressure from
the Ministry of Foreign Affairs,
外務省側の圧力で―
we won't be unveiling
our prototype weapons, either.
主力兵器の試作器
お披露目も なしだ
It's shaking the foundations of the company.
会社の屋台骨がガタガタだよ
サイード博士の死後も―
I hear you're pressing for large-scale water sales
even after Dr. Thied's death.
大規模な水の売却を
促しているとか
I have a duty to fulfill my contract.
契約を履行する義務がある
それに資源の有効活用は
国際社会の命題だ
And effective use of resources is key
for an international company.
There are some out there
who can't even secure drinking water.
（荒巻）飲み水すら
確保できない民族もいます
If you just want to criticize my economics,
I'm going back to work.
経済批判が目的なら
仕事に戻るよ
You're not cut out for government work.
君は国向けの人材ではないな
ＮＰＯでも作って
キャンプ暮らしでもしたまえ
Start an NPO and go live
in some refugee camp.
ムカつきますね
He's annoying.
He's a classic ex-politician,
and he owes me one from my intelligence days.
典型的な天下りで
情報部時代に貸しを作った
Which means he's a reliable source.
信頼できる筋というやつだ
NPOs, camps... and Foreign Affairs?
（イシカワ）ＮＰＯとキャンプ
それと 外務省か
The council on weapons development!
兵器開発審議会か
Was that the objective behind
the cyberterrorism against Harimadara?
ハリマダラ社へのサイバーテロは
そいつが目的か？
Lately there's a debate about
whether next-gen weapons
（サイトー）
次世代兵器の開発は―
should be produced domestically
or developed abroad.
国内生産か 国外開発かで
議論されてきた
事件で国内生産が
打撃を食うなら―
The overseas faction'd be thrilled
if a domestic manufacturer got attacked.
国外派は大喜びだ
Here we go: an NPO that
"treats cyberization disorders".
（イシカワ）あったぜ
“電脳化障害の治療”を行うＮＰＯ
戦時中に
クザン領内の難民キャンプで―
They disseminated cyberization and learning devices
in refugee camps in Kuzan during the war.
電脳化と学習装置の普及を行ってる
And domestically?
国内はどうだ？
Got a hit on that girl
in the same NPO's treatment records.
（イシカワ）例の娘が
同じＮＰＯの治療記録でヒット
Cyberization rejection syndrome.
電脳化拒絶症候群…
Apparently she ran away
戦災孤児の施設で
電脳化を拒んで脱走したらしい
from a war orphan facility
because she rejected being cyberized.
Not wanting a cyberbrain means you're sick?
電脳化を嫌がることが病気？
（イシカワ）大戦後 厚労省が
出した電脳化白書によれば―
The white paper on cyberization
the MHLW released after the war
classifies it with anorexia.
拒食症と同じ分類さ
（サイトー）知らなかったな…
That's news to me.
The cyberization business is insanely big money.
（イシカワ）電脳化ビジネスは
バカでかい金の流れを生んだんだ
Pretty predictable that people
who don't want it get treated as sick.
それが嫌だと言うやつは―
病人扱いされても
不思議じゃねえのさ
Could she be a genuine multiple personality?
（サイトー）
本当に多重人格者って可能性は？
（イシカワ）人格が分裂しても
ゴーストは１つってのが常識だがな
The prevailing theory is that
personalities split but Ghosts don't.
The issue is, what did that NPO
（素子）問題は そのＮＰＯが―
have to do with a business deal motivated
by military development?
軍事開発によってリードされた
企業取引に どう関係したかだ
戦時ビジネスに関わった軍人と企業
両方から攻めろ
Go at the military-industrial complex from
both ends: soldiers and companies.
（実行犯３）
俺だ 仲間は捕まっちまった
It's me. The others got caught.
（殺し屋）
心配ない 全員あの世で会える
Don't worry, you'll see them in the afterlife.
Hello!
（ボーマ）こんちわー
はっ け… 警察か？
Y-You a cop?
う… ぐおっ
じ… 自供の用意がある
弁護士に連絡を…
L-I prepared a confession.
Let me call my lawyer--
うがあああ！
お前に そんなチャンスはねえよ
You're not getting that chance.
餌を殺しやがって
たっぷりしゃべってもらうぜ
You killed our bait,
so you're gonna tell us everything.
Started to miss your old home?
（クルツ）
故郷が懐かしくなったか？
参考人を連行しただけだ
クルツ中佐
I'm only hereto bring in your witness,
Lt. Col. Kurutsu.
ツムギが待機中だ
Tsumugi is standing by.
Dive if you want to.
お前が潜りたければ そうしろ
ゴーストがあればだがな
Assuming she has a Ghost, that is.
What do you mean?
どういう意味？
I'm stepping out.
（クルツ）私は席を外す
委員会メンバーとして―
As a member of the committee,
I need to be at Harimadara's product inspection.
ハリマダラ製品の検査に
立ち会うのでな
（素子）まだ 出世願望に
とりつかれているのか？
Still obsessed with getting promoted?
（クルツ）
お前がやらずに 逃げ出したことだ
It's something you ran away without doing.
（トグサ）いやっ あっ…
（ツムギ１）久しいな 草薙
Nice to see you, Kusanagi.
I didn't think we'd have
another chance to work with you.
（ツムギ２）
こうしてまた 一緒に働けるとは
Are these your men?
（ツムギ１）彼らが君の部下かね
Yes. Batou and Togusa.
（素子）ええ バトーにトグサ
This is Tsumugi Dokuro.
They're both cyber warfare tactical officers.
こちらはツムギ ドクロ
２人とも電子戦の技術士官よ
"Both"?
Are they sharing a body?
２人って…
義体を共有してるのか？
She says they're two identical twins
in one conjoined body.
一卵性双生児の二重義体だとよ
I dunno how they move.
どうやって動いてんのか
俺にも分からねえ
すごいのがいるんだな
The world's full of surprises.
Let's get started.
（ツムギ２）それでは始めよう
So, only the body came back.
（ツムギ１）
やはり 戻ったのは義体だけか
What do you mean?
（素子）どういうこと？
She's a technical officer in
Lt. Col. Kurutsu's command.
（ツムギ２）彼女は
クルツ中佐付きの電子戦技官だ
She was investigating a hacker
with a special neurochip-type cyberbrain.
彼女は 特殊なニューロチップ型
電脳を持つハッカーを探索していた
He's known as "Scarecrow",
（ツムギ１）通称 スケアクロウ
and he's a suspect in the terrorist
attack on Harimadara.
ハリマダラ社を襲った
サイバーテロの容疑者だ
Another Oz character?
（トグサ）スケアクロウ…
今度はカカシか
（バトー）あん？
Huh?
Our conclusion is that he's a special spy
based on postwar tech.
（ツムギ２）
私たちの結論では―
戦後の技術をベースとした
特殊なスパイだ
Emma was the one who reasoned it out.
（ツムギ１）
推論を構築したのはエマでね
She hypothesized a hacker
with the same disorder she had.
彼女は自分と同じ障害を持つ人物を
想定した
少しずつ脳を
ニューロチップに置き換え―
Someone who had to incrementally
replace his brain with neurochips
and prosthetize his body to survive.
体を義体化せねば生きられない
彼女自身が その障害を？
She had that disorder?
Personality attenuates, and self hood can't be
retained without auxiliary cyberbrains.
（ツムギ２）人格は希薄化し
補助電脳なしでは自我を保てない
そういう障害を
自らの特質としたのが―
Emma transformed her impairment
into her signature trait, as did Scarecrow.
エマであり スケアクロウだ
Emma regularly used advanced cyberization
to structure her self hood,
（ツムギ１）
エマは高度電脳化による
自我構築を行っていたが―
スケアクロウは違う
but Scarecrow is different.
To compensate for his attenuated personality,
he dubs the Ghosts of others,
希薄な人格の代わりに
他者のゴーストをダビングし―
steals their bodies,
and assumes their identities.
義体を奪って本人に成り済ます
Like the scarecrow who can't think
inserting a false brain into his head.
（ツムギ２）知恵のないカカシに
偽物の脳を入れるようにな
マジかよ
Seriously?
つまり こいつが…
In other words, this is...
（ツムギ１）義体はエマだが
動かしているのは―
The body is Emma's,
but it's being operated by a man's brain
通常の３分の１ほどの
大きさしかない―
which is only one-third the normal size
and cyberized with neurochips.
ニューロチップで
高度電脳化された男の脳だ
So what I dived into was
the girl's dubbed Ghost.
私がダイブしたのは―
カカシにダビングされた娘の
ゴーストだった…
本人の脳はどうしたんだ？
What happened to her brain?
Ghost Dubbing would've degraded it.
ゴーストダビングで劣化した脳だ
It's either in the trash or sliced up
in his research lab.
処分されたか
実験用に切り刻まれたか
そんな…
That's awful...
Poor Emma. I'm sorry.
（ブリンダジュニア）
かわいそうなエマ ごめんなさい
It's okay, Junior. Don't be afraid.
（エマ）いいの ジュニア
怖がらないで
I know the lions will come.
The people with courage...
必ずライオンが来るわ
勇気を持った人たちが…
Who are you?
Tell me who you work for.
お前は何者だ？
所属機関を言え
I am a scarecrow.
My brain is fading away.
（ブリンダジュニア）僕はカカシ
脳がなくなっていく
（エマ）私はブリキ
心がなくなっていく
I am tin.
My heart is fading away.
Is that Emma talking, or her dubbed Ghost?
（バトー）
どっちが しゃべってんだ？
本人か
ダビングされたゴーストか
Tin Girl, give me the scarecrow man's name.
（素子）
ブリキ娘 カカシ男の名を言え
（エマ）
彼の名は ブリンダジュニア
His name is Brinda Jr.
Please, don't blame him.
お願い 彼を責めないで
Got a hit at a postwar nursing home./
And the same NPO is involved with it.
（イシカワ）
戦後の養護施設でヒット
ここにも例のＮＰＯが関わってる
Brinda Jr., age 32.
ブリンダジュニア 32歳
電脳化のあと
職業紹介所で会計士に
After he was cyberized,
he became an accountant at an employment agency.
人格は希薄でも―
His personality's thin,
but he memorized a ZOO-digit number
in two seconds for an IO fest.
知能テストで200桁の数字を
２秒で記憶してるぜ
That's textbook for someone with
special cognitive abilities.
（素子）
典型的な特殊認知能力者だ
Find out' which organization
set' him up as a hacker.
どの機関がハッカーに
仕立て上げたか特定しろ
（イシカワ）了解
Roger.
I'm diving into that man's Ghost.
私が あの男のゴーストに
ダイブするわ
（ツムギ１）
ダブルゴーストの実例は
世界でも数件だ
There are only a handful of
proven double Ghosts in existence.
We don't know the dangers.
どんな危険があるか分からない
I want to know which Ghost has motive.
（素子）２つのゴーストの
どちらに動機があるか―
突き止めたいの
（ツムギ２）エマを疑うのか？
彼女は犠牲者だ
You're doubting Emma?
She's the victim here.
それを確かめる
Then I'll confirm that.
バトー 逆侵入に備えて
ディフェンダーを頼むわ
Batou, be my backup
in case they back-hack me.
Two against two, eh?
相手が２人なら こっちも２人か
Togusa. Get all the records copied.
トグサ
記録をコピーさせてもらえ
Roger. Oh, here...
Sorry, it's a call from my dad.
（トグサ）了解
…と すみません おやじから電話で
Hey Dad, it's been a while. Yeah.
久しぶりだな おやじ ああ…
Batou! Restrain Togusa!
バトー トグサを拘束しろ！
分かった
俺がライオンになる
Got it. I'll become the Lion.
（バトー）
ええいっ まだマテバかよ
A Mateba, still?
Don't move!
（素子）動くな！
（イバチ）ふんがっ！
ふん！
ふがっ！
少佐！
Major!
Let's go.
（トグサ）行こう
This is crazy! I found a Starter log
on his comm-it's the virus!
（イシカワ）何てこった
通信にスターターのログを発見
例のウイルスだ
He must have kept the virus inactive
within his neurochips.
（ツムギ１）ニューロチップ内で
ウイルスを不活性状態にしていたか
His infiltration was unexpectedly quick.
予想外の侵入速度だ
（ツムギ２）敵意を抱いた記憶と
目の前の対象を結合し―
So, it combines victims' memories of past hostility
with objects in front of them
to plant instantaneous false memories?
瞬間性の疑似記憶を植え付けるのか
（イバチ）ぬあっ
I can get deadly, right?
マジでやっていいんだな？
でないと 一瞬でやられるわよ
That was your last breath if you don't.
Don't underestimate me!
ナメるんじゃねえ
The scarecrow is the virus's host
and Togusa's brain is the package, right?
（素子）
ウイルスのホストがカカシ男で―
パッケージはトグサの脳だな
Yep. But the infection route's disturbingly selective.
だが 感染経路が いやに選択的だ
Only people around you are being infected.
少佐の周囲だけ感染している
Does that mean the onset can be regulated?
（素子）発症を操作できる
ウイルスということか？
That'd be impossible without
a third party to switch it on.
（イシカワ）
スターターのスイッチを入れる
第三者がいなきゃ不可能だ
Which I guess means it's a virus
whose damage can be controlled.
つまり 被害をコントロールできる
ウイルスってことか？
Then it's military.
Reanalyze yesterday's infection data.
（素子）ならば 軍事用だ
きのうの感染データを再解析しろ
追うのはウイルスじゃない
スターターを持つ敵だ
We don't want to chase the virus;
we want to chase the enemy in possession of it.
（エマ）
私は 死んだあとでも生き続けたい
I wish to go on living even after my death.
Hidden data?
（イシカワ）隠しデータ？
For these 620 reasons,
we oppose cyberization without free choice.
（エマ･ブリンダジュニア）
私たちは620通りの理由により―
選択の自由のない電脳化に
反対します
Reason: We submit that software
within the cyberbrain
一つ 私たちは
電脳内に存在する第三者による―
is vulnerable to third-party tampering.
改ざんが可能なソフトウェアの
ぜい弱性を指摘します
Reason: Electronic alteration of
memory causes abnormalities
一つ 私たちの“ゴースト”と
呼ばれる主体的意志の総体は―
in the totality of our independent
will referred to as the ”Ghost'”.
電子的手段による
記憶の改変によって―
変調を来します
Do you actually think a world
without infection and infiltration is possible?!
（素子）感染も侵入も受けずに
いられる世界が―
あると思っているのか？
（素子）ツムギ 生きてる？
Tsumugi! You alive?
I'm running a sim of the scarecrow's brain.
Help me.
逃げたカカシの脳を
シムライズするわ 手伝って
You have Emma Tsuda's Ghost infiltration key,
don't you? Make me a backdoor.
ツダ･エマのゴースト侵入キーを
持ってるでしょ？
バックドアを流して
（ツムギ１）なるほど…
I see, you're going to use
Scarecrow's cyberbrain structure
スケアクロウの電脳構成をもとに
ワクチンらしきものを作るか
to approximate a vaccine?
ぐっ… ハァ ハァ…
（エマ･ブリンダジュニア）
一つ 私たちの記憶は―
Reason: There are currently seventeen
possible ways to alter our memories.
現時点で17パターンの手段で
改変が可能です
（トグサ）くそっ！
Shit!
少佐！
Major! Why won't you use my Ghost
infiltration key to stop this?!
なんで 俺のゴースト侵入キーを
使って止めないんです！
It's no use.
Brinda won't let her.
（エマ）
無駄よ ブリンダがやらせない
I will become anyone.
I've inputted and erased many Ghosts.
（ブリンダジュニア）
僕は誰にでもなる
たくさんのゴーストを入れて消した
I disappeared, too... Who am I?
僕も消えた 僕は誰？
501機関も攻撃対象だったのか？
Was Unit 501 a target, too?
Aren't you a victim after all?!
君は犠牲者じゃなかったのか！？
There was no other way.
他に方法がなかったの
何が目的なんだ？
What are you after?
Don't disappear, Emma.
（ブリンダジュニア）
消えないで エマ
Let's go on living after our deaths, together.
２人で 死んだあとも
生き続けましょう
They're here.
来たわ
An attack barrier!
（素子）攻性防壁！
（バトー）少佐！
Major!
（ホヅミ）うっ…
（ニグチ）大佐！
Colonel!
They fought each other with attack barriers.
One of them got forwarded.
（ホヅミ）
やつらが攻性防壁でやり合った
一方を転送されたな
我々のものより強力とは…
I can't believe it was stronger than ours...
You were infiltrated for a moment.
（ヤノザキ）
一瞬ですが侵入されました
Delete all relevant operational headquarters
from the cyberbrain Net.
（ホヅミ）電脳ネット内の
当該作戦本部をデリート
Go after Brinda.
There's nothing left to do here.
ブリンダを追え
もう ここに用はない
野良犬が…
Damn stray dog...
Looks like we pulled it off.
（バトー）
何とか成功したみたいだな
The host and Starter are still active.
（素子）ホストもスターターも
まだ活動中よ
We can see the ocean, Emma.
（ブリンダジュニア）
海が見えるよ エマ
（イシカワ）
ハァ… さすがに肝が冷えたぜ 少佐
This creeps even me out, Major.
Report.
進展は？
Col. Hozumi from Army intelligence
was the one to recruit Brinda Jr.
（イシカワ）ブリンダジュニアを
スカウトしたのは―
陸軍情報部 ホヅミ大佐
"Scarecrow" is an op cooked up
by their old Investigations Section
“スケアクロウ”ってのは
旧調査部で考案された作戦で―
during a period when they were
working on Ghost Dub devices.
ゴーストダビング装置が
開発されたころのものだ
Hozumi got on the Next-Gen Weapons
Review Committee through Foreign Affairs.
（サイトー）ホヅミ大佐は
外省サイドを介し―
主力兵器検討委員会に参加
But she wasn't there long,
and Kurutsu of Unit 501 took her seat
だが 間もなく委員を外れ―
代わりに国防省の
北原副大臣の推薦で―
at Vice-Minister Kitahara's recommendation.
501機関のクルツ中佐が後任に
Unit 501 got a hold on Hozumi
through military musical chairs, eh?
軍人同士の椅子取りゲームで―
501機関が
ホヅミの弱みを握ったな
Reason." We can prove that false memories
（エマ･ブリンダジュニア）一つ
私たちは偽りの記憶によって―
- compel us to commit murder, suicide,
and other criminal acts.
殺人 自殺 その他の
犯罪的行為を強制…
- Which one built the pod? - compel us to commit'
murder, suicide, and other criminal acts.
ボットは どっちが作成した？
Unknown. But Army intelligence decided to
rally by interfering with the Review Committee.
不明だ
ただ 陸軍情報部は
巻き返しのため検討委員会に干渉
I'd guess that somewhere in there,
the two hackers became aware of each other.
そのどこかで２人のハッカーが
互いを認識したんだろう
（素子）ハリマダラへの
サイバーテロが接点か
The attack on Harimadara is the connection?
There's no evidence they did it.
あれがやつらの仕業という
証拠はない
ただし ホヅミ大佐は
兵器開発の国外派で―
But Hozumi is in the overseas
weapons development faction,
ハリマダラは国内派の牙城だ
and Harimadara's a domestic faction stronghold.
Who shot our bait?
（素子）餌を撃ち殺した男は？
A Kuzan water cartel hit man.
Hozumi's playing with serious fire.
（パズ）
クザン水企業カルテルの殺し屋だ
ホヅミ大佐は
相当 ヤバい橋を渡ってる
She used the pretext of wartime industry
大戦中 クザンに駐留した際―
to interfere in Kuzan's affairs while
she was stationed there during the war.
戦時ビジネスを盾に
内政干渉を行ったんだ
もし 国内派を押さえられず
約束した利益を提供できなきゃ―
If she can't subdue the domestic faction
and give the cartel the profits she promised,
it'll retaliate against her.
カルテルは大佐に報復する
Starter analysis results?
スターターの解析は？
（イシカワ）特定できず
Couldn't pin down the trigger,
but I got my answer
ただ ９課がドミネを
実行していたにもかかわらず―
from the fact that we couldn't find
the infection route into the building
地上からビル内への感染経路が
不明だった点で答えが出た
even though Section 9 had domination over it.
Ｃ４ＩＳＲ用回線だ
It was a C4ISR network.
A military communications system.
（バトー）軍の情報通信システムか
真相が見えてきたな
Things are starting to come clear.
Col. Hozumi's the one who activated Starter
スターターを起動させたのも―
回線をつなげてＶＩＰルームの
ＳＰを感染させたのも―
and patched the virus through
to infect the VIP room's security.
ホヅミ大佐だ
She was after the woman the guard shot.
（バトー）
狙いは ＳＰが撃った相手…
Senior Vice-Minister Kitahara,
who's with the domestic faction.
（素子）
兵器国内開発派の北原副大臣だ
That massacre was a smokescreen
for one murder?!
１人を殺す隠れみのに虐殺を？
フンッ 根っからの戦争好きなのさ
Guess she's a born war-lover.
（サイトー）
現場でブリキ娘を狙撃した理由は？
Why snipe Tin Girl?
（素子）ブラフよ
That was a bluff.
私たちを排除し 安全にブリキを
501に送り込みたかったのね
She must've wanted to get rid of us
and get Tin Girl safely to the 501 .
So her little visit to Section 9
was a smokescreen, too?
９課への引き渡し要求も
隠れみのか
She backed down so easily
because she was after Unit 501 from the start.
あっさり引き下がったのは
そもそも501が狙いだからよ
ツダ･エマという反電脳主義者を
虐殺騒ぎの主犯にするために
So she could set up anti-cyberbrainist
Emma Tsuda as the massacre's ringleader.
ハリマダラ 副大臣 501
Harimadara, the Vice-Minister, the 501
She had a threefold plan to take them all out!
三面作戦で全て潰す気だった…
What about the Ghost of the girl
who got dubbed?
（バトー）
ダビングされた娘のゴーストは？
If she does have her own will,
why'd she knowingly let Hozumi use her?
あれに意志がある場合―
利用されたのが分かってて
なんで ホヅミに従う？
状況だけ見れば―
Just from the circumstances,
the scarecrow is the one you've been after.
少佐が追ってた相手は
カカシ男ってことになるが…
He didn't necessarily write the virus.
Hozumi said there was a broker.
（素子）
ウイルスの作者とは限らない
ホヅミは
ブローカーがいると言った
それが本当なら
ウイルスを作って売った者がいる
If she told the truth,
someone out there made and sold it.
That's who I'm after.
そいつが獲物だ
（バトー）全ては推測だ
This is all speculation.
Right now, there's only one way for us to get proof.
現時点で 俺たちが
確証をつかむ方法は１つしかない
（素子）
トグサの位置は確認したな？
I assume you have Togusa's location.
We'll meet en route.
経路上に集合
We're going to capture both Ghosts-
the scarecrow's, and the girl's.
カカシ男と娘 ２つのゴーストを
我々が確保する
Togusa's the problem.
（バトー）問題はトグサだ
Blowing a married teammate's
brains out ain't my job.
女房持ちの同僚の頭をぶち抜くのは
俺の仕事じゃねえ
We know for sure this infection
plants false memories, right?
感染で疑似記憶を
植え付けられるのは 確かだな？
死んだ父親と話してたの
見たでしょ？
You saw him talking to his dead father.
There should be a shared form.
（バトー）
共有フォームがあるはずだ
I'll get infected, so you ID it
and version up your makeshift vaccine.
俺が感染するから
そいつを特定して―
ワクチンもどきを
バージョンアップしろ
You want to mirror your own brain?
（素子）
自分の電脳にミラーする気？
Worst case scenario, blow my brains out.
（バトー）
最悪 俺の頭をぶち抜きゃいい
（素子）私の仕事ってわけ？
So that's my job?
If you don't like it, make me the leader.
嫌なら俺を隊長にしとけってんだよ
検問？
A checkpoint?
You're on the wanted list
as a suspected terrorist!
（バトー）
お前がテロ容疑で指名手配されてる
くそっ ９課だ
Shit, it's Section 9!
The ape used to be in Army intelligence.
サルは元陸軍情報部だぞ
He cut a deal with Hozumi,
and he's framing us!
ホヅミと取引して
俺たちをハメる気だ
She may just want us to think so.
I'll send Section 9 our intel.
（素子）そう思わせたいだけかも
９課に
こっちがつかんだ情報を送るわ
ここまで来て
まだ サルを頼るのか！？
After all this, you're still relying on him?!
（素子）違うわ
- No.
- Why, then?!
じゃあ なぜ？
そうささやくのよ
私のゴーストが
My Ghost is whispering that I should do it.
（トグサ）うっ… 待て！
Wait! Where are you going?!
どこへ行く気だ？
うう… 止まるんだ！
Stop!
（エマ･ブリンダジュニア）
遠くに行くって約束したんだ
We promised we'd go far away.
Goodbye.
（エマ）さよなら
I released the package!
（素子）パッケージを解除できたわ
I'm going on ahead.
先に行くわよ
I told you to shoot if things went south!
Take a damn gun with you...
ヤバいときは撃てっつったろ
銃ぐらい構えとけ
Major...
少佐…
She's in pieces!
（バトー）粉々じゃねえかよ
（素子）ニューロチップ式なら
まだ生きてる
If she's a neurochip version,
she's still alive.
（ブリンダジュニア）
僕たちは生き続ける
We'll go on living.
It's a Ghost Dub, not a transfer?!
転送ではなく
ゴーストダビングだと！
（サイトー）
ハリマダラの試作機体だ
That's a Harimadara prototype!
Major!
（イシカワ）少佐！
Two Ghosts have been
dubbed into that thing.
（素子）あれに２人のゴーストが
ダビングされた
止めるぞ ロジコマ！
ありったけ出せ
We're going to stop it! Logicomas,
give me everything you've got!
Yes, sir!
（ロジコマ１･ロジコマ２）
イエッサー！
Where the hell would they abandon
their own lives to go?
てめえの命を置き去りにして
どこへ行くってんだ？
海だ…
The ocean.
Huh?
あん？
They're not going anywhere!
This ends here!
（素子）どこへも行かせない
ここで終わりだ
Next-gen weapon or not,
its brains are rookies.
次世代主力兵器だろうが
脳は素人だ
Aim for the eyes and legs,
and it's a piece of cake.
目と足を狙えば楽勝だな
マジかよ
For real?!
（バトー）ていっ
（トグサ）うわっ
捕まえたぞ
Got you now!
何だ？
What's that?
It's Army intelligence!
The bastards requested an artillery strike!
（サイトー）陸軍情報部だ
砲撃を要請しやがった
You've cut off your sensory system?!
知覚系を切断しただと？
しまった！
Crap!
You discarded intensity regions...
義体信号域を捨てた
認識系 記憶野
自分を構成するネットを捨てて…
Recognition systems, memory fields,
the Net that maintains your architecture...
自分のゴーストすら切り捨て―
You even jettisoned your own Ghost!
You want a life you've stripped
all meaning from?!
何もかも意味消失させておきながら
生きるだと！
（ブリンダジュニア）さよなら
Goodbye.
（ホヅミ）終わったな
It's over.
Return to base.
We're going to Kuzan, by way of Benares.
基地へ戻れ
ベナレスを経由してクザンへ行く
世界の電脳経済は始まったばかりだ
The world's cyber economy has only just begun.
I'll pay whatever it takes to reconcile with the cartel--
カルテルと和解する金は
いくらでも…
On your knees, hands in the air!
（警察官）手を上げてひざまずけ！
例の手配書か
言わんこっちゃねえ
Oh, the wanted poster.
Told you so.
（クルツ）９課の部長と同じだな
You're just like that Section 9 chief.
埋められたものを暴いて回らないと
気が済まないのか？
Never happy unless you're digging up
what's dead and buried.
It's something you ran away without doing.
（素子）
お前がやらずに逃げ出したことだ
どうせ何も変わらないぞ 草薙
Nothing's going to change, Kusanagi.
We're an independent offensive unit.
私たちは独立攻性部隊だ
We stand independent of the system,
システムから自立し―
and we have truly discrete personalities
that don't get packaged.
パッケージ化されない
本当の単位としての人格を所有する
When we're officially approved
as top priority, we'll root out
我々が最優先ラインに
承認されたときは―
all the sorry bastards who conspire
because they're afraid of a scandal.
スキャンダルを恐れて
なれ合う くそ野郎どもを―
一掃してやる
（クルツ）
私も それに含まれると？
And you count me as one of them?
I never changed your channel.
Contact me whenever you want to come home.
お前のチャンネルは昔のままだ
古巣に戻りたくなったら
いつでも連絡しろ
（荒巻）釈放だ
You're free to go. We voided
the wanted notice Col. Hozumi put out.
ホヅミ大佐が出した手配書は
抹消した
Vice-Minister of Defense Kitahara
wants to thank you.
国防省の北原副大臣が
お前に礼を言いたがっている
それ 何かの冗談？
Is that some sort of joke?
A political one.
政治上のな
先ほど９課が
ホヅミ大佐が所有する物件で―
Section 9 just went through
Col. Hozumi's possessions
ゴーストダビング装置と―
and confiscated a Ghost Dub device
and an outline of the Scarecrow op.
スケアクロウ作戦の概要書を
押収した
They couldn't arrest her, though.
（素子）でも 逮捕はできなかった
No-but then she confessed.
（荒巻）ああ だが自分から吐いた
搭乗していたヘリが撃墜された
クザン製の武器でな
Her chopper was shot down
with Kuzan weapons.
She's afraid enough of the cartel's revenge
ホヅミ大佐はカルテルの報復を恐れ
保護拘束と司法取引を求めている
to request protective custody
and a plea bargain.
So she'll get let off scat-free.
（素子）つまり 裁かれない
I'll make sure she doesn't.
（荒巻）そうはさせん
The NPO she worked with is a front
for dirty cyberbrain business.
大佐が関与したＮＰＯは
悪質な電脳ビジネスの隠れみのだ
Not only that, we've detected Starter
in her cyberbrain, just like your intel said.
さらには お前の情報どおり―
大佐の電脳内で
スターターが検出された
She got a lot of people injured or killed,
and I'll make her pay for that-
多数を死傷させた罪は償ってもらう
even if I can't take her to court yet.
たとえ今は
表沙汰にできなくともだ
Where did she get the virus?
（素子）
大佐は どこでウイルスを？
Through a broker, she says.
She claims to know nothing about its author.
（荒巻）ブローカーを介して
入手したそうだ
作成者については
何も知らんと言っている
（素子）そう…
I see.
Was it really the cartel
who tried to kill Hozumi?
大佐を狙ったのは
本当にカルテルか？
Even if it was someone who wanted to
prevent us from investigating her,
大佐に捜査の手が及んでほしくない
誰かがいたとしても―
とっくに痕跡を消してるでしょうね
I'm sure any trace of them is long gone.
Major.
（トグサ）少佐
（素子）がん首そろえて出迎え？
All of you came?
I didn't know I had such admirable subordinates.
そんなに殊勝な隊員たちだとはね
拘留中に
襲撃される可能性があるしな
You could've been attacked
while in custody.
We've been keeping an eye on
all the suspicious characters who came by.
怪しいやつを
片っ端からマークしてたのさ
（せきばらい）
（荒巻）もう一つ
One more thing.
I told the Minister of Home Affairs
内務大臣には―
that your team contributed to deterring the virus.
お前たちが ウイルス抑止に
貢献したことを伝えた
Use your vaunted cyberbrain to read
Public Security Commission report N2077.
得意の電脳で 公安審議会レポート
Ｎ2077を参照しろ
As of tomorrow, you get special authority.
明日付けで お前たちに
特務権限が与えられる
監査部のチャンネルなしでな
Without official oversight.
This case isn't over.
事件は まだ終わってはいない
高度な電脳ハックを可能とする
ウイルス 関与した組織…
Investigate the high-level hacking virus
and any organizations involved,
and plan to attend plenty of funerals
along the way.
多数の死者を弔う気で捜査しろ
私がサイードを撃ったわ
I shot Thied.
You must have had a hunch that
an intelligence bigwig was behind this,
相手が情報部の大物だと
薄々知ってて―
meaning you would've wanted
an intel advantage at any cost.
何が何でも
情報勝ちしたかったはずよ
なのに なぜ止めなかったの？
So why didn't you stop me?!
（荒巻）
お前のゴースト侵入キーなど
持っとらんからだ
Because I don't have
your Ghost infiltration key.
No organization will ever have it.
（荒巻）どんな組織も
未来永劫(えいごう) 持つことはない
I promised your late commander that.
それが
お前の上司だった男との約束だ
Bottom line, all we figured out
was that someone out there
（バトー）結局 俺たちが
フォローできたのは―
used a couple of anti-cyberbrainist hackers
and a miserable water company chick.
２人の反電脳主義的ハッカーと
水企業の哀れな女が―
利用されたってことだけか
We may be looking for a crime
worth sacrificing lives over,
（素子）多数の死者に値する
事件性を求めても―
but all we have are money-mad war profiteers
あるのは戦時ビジネスの亡者と―
and a man and girl obsessed
with casting things away.
捨てることにとりつかれた
男と娘だけよ
For now, that is.
今はまだね
（バトー）男と娘
どっちが主体だったんだ？
Which one had agency, the man or the girl?
Did they even have real will?
そもそも まともな意志なんて
あったのか？
When they blocked my infiltration, at least.
（素子）少なくとも
私の侵入を防いだときはね
But they fled with nowhere to go,
then had to transfer into that weapon.
（バトー）だが
行く当てのない逃亡の末―
あんな兵器に
ゴーストを移すしかなかった
That think-tank's cyberbrain had
a massive output system.
あの思考戦車の電脳…
大規模な出力系も備えてたわ
Hmm?
彼らが自分を構成するものを
切り捨てたのは―
What if the reason they cast away
what made them themselves
最後に残ったもの
ネットに出力するためだとしたら…
was to output the last thing left into the Net?
You think that's where they were going?
それが亡命先だってのか？
ゴーストの最後のかけらを
ネットに流して…
Pouring the last shreds of their Ghosts
into the Net... Is that even possible?
可能なのか？ そんなこと
研究はされてるけど
実証は不可能よ
It's been researched,
but it's impossible to prove.
ただ―
But in the moment their Ghosts were lost,
I got the feeling they'd fused.
彼らのゴーストロストの瞬間
１つになった気がした
That two lives had become one...
２つの命が１つに…
That isn't like you. Ghosts are
the most independent things in this world.
（バトー）らしくねえな
ゴーストは
この世で最も独立した存在だ
Even the ones being controlled are fundamentally,
eternally standalone.
操作されたものでも
本質は永遠のスタンドアローンさ
Like our squad, yeah?
俺たちの部隊みたいにな
Yeah.
そうね
Well? The floaters are all ready.
I got a set of two.
（バトー）で？
フローターの準備できてるぜ
ペアで浮き袋 ２セット
Even someone with
a titanium skull wouldn't drown.
チタン製の頭蓋骨だろうが
沈みっこねえ
本気で真冬の海に潜りたいわけ？
You seriously want to swim
in the ocean in midwinter?
Gotta shake off those memories
of almost drowning.
（バトー）
沈みかけた記憶を追っ払うのさ
Plus it ain't too often
I get to see you in a swimsuit.
お前の水着姿なんて
そうそう拝めねえし
それが目的？
That's your real goal?
あん？
（素子）あきれた
- Huh?
- Unbelievable.
違うって！
俺は お前のためにだな…
No, no! I'm doing this all for you!
I'll take a rain check.
（素子）
またの機会にしておくわ
（バトー）
おい 違うって言ってんだろ！
I'm telling you, you got it all wrong!
A Team Nanban (594mgnav) Release